201 Edge Drive Norcross PA 17001 March 14, 2012

Mr James Vernon Personnel Director M-Global Inc 105 Halsey Street Baltimore MD 21212

Dear Mr. Vernon:

My academic adviser, Professor Sam Singleton, informed me about an electrical engineering opening at M-Global, where he worked until last year. I am writing to apply for the job.

I understand that M-Global is making a major effort to build a full-scale equipment development laboratory. That prospect interests me greatly because of my academic background in electrical engineering. At Northern Tech, I took courses in several subjects that might be useful in the lab's work—for example, microprocessor applications, artificial intelligence, and fiber optics.

Also, related work at Jones Energy & Automation, Inc., has given me experience building and developing new electronics systems. In particular, my work as an assembler taught me the importance of precision and quality control. I'd like the opportunity to apply this knowledge at M-Global.

Personal business will take me to Baltimore April 8–10. Could you meet with me on one of those days to discuss how M-Global might use my skills? Please let me know if an interview would be convenient at that time.

Enclosed is a résumé that highlights my credentials. I hope to be talking with you in June.

Sincerely, Donald V*izano*-

Donald Vizano

Enclosure: Résumé

Donald Vizano 201 Edge Drive Norcross PA 17001 (300) 555-7861 dvizano@nct.edu

OBJECTIVE: A full-time position in electrical engineering,

with emphasis on designing new equipment in

automation and microprocessing

EDUCATION: 2006–2012 Bachelor of Science in Electrical

Engineering (expected June 2012) Northern College of Technology, Shipley, PA 3.5 GPA (out of 4.0 scale)

Major Courses:

Fiber Optics Artificial Machine Intelligence
Automated Manufacturing Systems Communication Control Systems

Microcomputer Applications
Microcomputer Systems

Digital Control Systems

Semiconductor Circuits and Devices

Related Courses:

Information Systems Programming Languages
Business Communication Engineering Economy
Industrial Psychology Technical Communication

Other Skills: Fluent in Spanish

ACTIVITIES

AND HONORS: Institute of Electrical and Electronic Engineering (IEEE)

Dean's List, eight quarters.

EMPLOYMENT:

2008–2012 Electronic Assembler (part time)

Jones Energy & Automation, Inc.

Banner, PA

2007–2008 Lab Monitor (part time)

Computer Services

Northern College of Technology

Shipley, PA

REFERENCES: Available upon request

1523 River Lane Worthville OH 43804 August 6, 2012

Mr Willard Yancy Director, Automotive Systems XYZ Motor Company, Product Development Division Charlotte NC 28202

Dear Mr. Yancy:

Recently I have been researching the leading national companies in automotive computer systems. Your job ad in the July 6 *National Business Employment Weekly* caught my eye because of XYZ's innovations in computer-controlled safety systems. I would like to apply for the automotive computer engineer job.

Your advertisement notes that experience in computer systems for machinery or robotic systems would be a plus. I have had extensive experience in the military with computer systems, ranging from a digital communications computer to an air-traffic-control training simulator. In addition, my college experience includes courses in computer engineering that have broadened my experience. I am eager to apply what I have learned to your company.

My mechanical knowledge was gained from growing up on my family's dairy farm. After watching and learning from my father, I learned to repair internal combustion engines, diesel engines, and hydraulic systems. Then for five years I managed the entire dairy operation.

With my training and hands-on experience, I believe I can contribute to your company. Please contact me at 614/555-2731 if you wish to arrange an interview.

Sincerely,

James M. Sistrunk

James M Sistrunk

Enclosure: Résumé

James M Sistrunk jmsistrunk@tmail.com 1523 River Lane Worthville OH 43804 (614) 555-2731

Professional Objective:

To contribute to the research, design, and development of automotive computer control systems

Education:

B.S., Computer Engineering, 2009–present Columbus College, Columbus, Ohio

Major concentration in Control Systems with minor in Industrial Engineering. Courses included Microcomputer Systems, Digital Control Systems, and several different programming courses.

Computer Repair Technician Certification Training, 2006–2007

U.S. Air Force Technical Training Center, Keesler Air Force Base, Biloxi, MS

General Computer Systems Option with emphasis on mainframe computers. Student leader in charge of processing and orientation for new students from basic training.

Career Development:

Computer Repair Technician, U.S. Air Force, 2005–2007

Secret Clearance

Responsibilities and duties included:

- Repair of computer systems
- Preventive maintenance inspections
- Diagnostics and troubleshooting of equipment

Accomplishments included:

- "Excellent" score during skills evaluation
- Award of an Air Force Specialty Code "5" skill level

Assistant Manager, Spring Farm, Wootan, Ohio, 2000–2005 Responsible for dairy operations on this 500-acre farm. Developed management and technical skills; learned to repair

Special Skills:

Adobe Creative Suite Microsoft Word Object Oriented Languages

sophisticated farm equipment.

C++ Programming

References:

Available upon request

456 Cantor Way #245 Gallop Minnesota 55002 September 3, 2012

Ms Judith R Gonzalez American Hospital Systems 3023 Center Avenue Randolf Minnesota 55440

Dear Ms. Gonzalez:

My placement center recently informed me about the Management Trainee opening with Mercy Hospital. As a business major with experience working in hospitals, I wish to apply for the position.

Your job advertisement notes that you seek candidates with a broad academic background in business and an interest in hospital management. At Central State College, I've taken extensive course work in three major areas in business: finance, marketing, and personnel management. This broad-based academic curriculum has provided me a solid foundation for a wide variety of management tasks at Mercy Hospital.

My summer and part-time employment also matches the needs of your position. While attending Central State, I've worked part time and summers as an assistant in the Business Office at Grady Hospital. That experience has acquainted me with the basics of business management within the context of a mid-sized hospital, much like Mercy.

The enclosed résumé highlights the skills that match your Management Trainee opening. I would like the opportunity to talk with you in person and can be reached at 612-555-1111 for an interview.

Sincerely,

Denise Ware Sanborn

Doniso Waro Santona

Denise Ware Sanborn sanborndenise@cscm.edu 456 Cantor Way #245 Gallop Minnesota 55002 612-555-1111

Objective

Entry-level management position in the health care industry. Seek position that includes exposure to a wide variety of management and business-related tasks.

Education

Bachelor of Arts Degree, June 2012 Central State College Gallop, Minnesota

Major: Business Administration

Grade Point Average: 3.26 of possible 4.0, with 3.56 in all major courses All college expenses financed by part-time and summer work at Grady Hospital in St. Paul, Minnesota.

Skills and Experience

Finance

Helped with research for three fiscal-year budgets Developed new spreadsheet for monthly budget reports Wrote accounts payable correspondence

Marketing

Solicited copy from managers for new brochure Designed and edited new brochure

Participated in team visits to 10 area physicians

Personnel

Designed new performance appraisal form for secretarial staff Interviewed applicants for Maintenance Department jobs Coordinated annual training program for nursing staff

Awards

2012 Arden Award for best senior project in the Business Administration Department (paper that examined Total Quality Management)

Dean's list for six semesters

References

Academic and work references available upon request.

2389 Jenson Court Gulfton MS 39200 (601) 555-1111 February 18, 2012

Mr Nigel Pierce Personnel Director Structural Systems Inc 105 Paisley Way Jackson MS 39236

Dear Mr. Pierce:

I am writing in response to your ad for a technical representative in the July 13 (Sunday) edition of the *Jackson Journal*. I believe my experience in construction and my degree in civil engineering technology make me an excellent candidate for this position.

I am very familiar with your products for the wood construction market. The laminated beams and floor joists your company manufactures were specified by many of the architects I have worked with during my co-op experience at Mississippi College. Work I have done in the residential and small commercial construction industry convinced me of the advantages of your products over nominal lumber.

Enclosed is my résumé, which focuses on the skills gained from my co-op work that would transfer to your firm. I look forward to meeting you and discussing my future with your company.

Sincerely,

Todd L. Fisher

Jodd L. Fisher

Enclosure: Résumé

Todd L Fisher 2389 Jenson Court Gulfton MS 39200 (601) 555-1111 tlfish@ail.com

PROFESSIONAL

OBJECTIVE Use my education in civil engineering and my

construction experience to assume a technical

advisory position.

EDUCATION Mississippi College

Hart, Mississippi; Bachelor of Science,

Civil Engineering Technology

June 2011, GPA: 3.00 (out of 4.00)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Financed education by working as co-op

student for two Jackson construction firms for

18 months.

Design Skills Assisted with the layout and design of wall

panels for Ridge Development condominium

project.

Created layout and design for complete roof and floor systems for numerous churches and

small commercial projects.

Computer Skills Introduced computerization to the design

offices of a major construction company (HP hardware in HPbasic operating system).

Designed trusses on Sun workstations in the UNIX operating system. Operated as the

system administrator for the office.

Leadership Skills Instructed new computer-assisted design

(CAD) operators on the operation of design software for panel layout and design.

software for parier layout and design.

Designed and implemented management

system for tracking jobs in plant.

REFERENCES References available upon request.



Karen S Patel

300 Park Drive Birtingdale NY 20092 (210) 555-2112 KSPatel@tmail.net

OBJECTIVE Position as in-house technical writer and as trainer in

communication skills

EDUCATION Sumpter College, Marist, Vermont

M.S. in Technical Communication, GPA: 4.0, December 2011

Warren College, Aurora, New York M.A. in English, Cum Laude, June 2009

University of Bombay, India

B.A. in English, First Class Honors, June 2005

EMPLOYMENT

Editing/Writing

Public Relations Office, Sumpter College 2010-present

Administrative Assistant: Write press releases and conduct interviews. Publish news stories in local newspapers and in

Sumpter Express. Edit daily campus newsletter.

Hawk Newspapers, Albany, New York, 2007–2008

Warren College Internship: Covered and reported special events; conducted interviews; assisted with proofreading, layout, headline count. Scanned newspapers for current events; conducted research for stories. Published feature

stories.

Teaching/Research Sumpter College, Marist, Vermont, 2010–2011

Teaching Assistant: Tutored English at the Writing Center, answered "Grammar Hotline" phone questions, edited and critiqued student papers, taught English to non-English speakers, and helped students prepare for Regents exams.

Warren College, Aurora, New York, 2008-2009

Teaching Assistant: Taught business writing, supervised peer editing and in-class discussions, held student

conferences, and graded students' papers.

Research Assistant: Verified material by checking facts, wrote brief reports related to research, researched

information and bibliographies.

COMPUTER SKILLS Microsoft Office, Adobe Creative Suite, Adobe Technical

Communication Suite

REFERENCES Available upon request

SUSAN A MARTIN

SCHOOL ADDRESS 540 Wood Drive Bama CA 90012 (901) 555-2222

PERMANENT ADDRESS 30 Avon Place Atlas, CA 90000 (901) 555-6074

E-MAIL

smartin@piercecollege.edu

OBJECTIVE

Analyze and solve problems involving natural and pollution control systems as an Environmental Scientist

EDUCATION

Pierce College, Bama, California

Bachelor of Science, Environmental Science

May 2012, GPA: 3.15 (out of 4.00)

Pleasant Valley College, Barnes, Nevada

Associate in Applied Science, Engineering Science

May 2010, GPA: 3.20 (out of 4.00)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Research Skills:

- * Worked as lab assistant in a research project to analyze the effect of acid rain on frog reproduction in Lake Lane.
- $\ensuremath{^{\star}}$ Designed Pierce College computer program to analyze data on ozone depletion.

Leadership Skills:

- * Taught inventory procedures to new employees of Zane's Office Supply.
- \star Helped incoming freshmen and transfer students adjust to Pierce College as dormitory resident assistant.

Organizational Skills:

- * Maintained academic department files as student assistant in Environmental Science Department.
- * Organized field trips for Pierce College Mountaineering Club.

HONORS AND ACTIVITIES

Dean's list (five semesters) President of Cycling Club

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Dormitory Resident Assistant, Peirce College, Bama, CA 2011-2012 Trainer, Zane's Office Supply, Bama, CA, 2010-2011

REFERENCES

References and transcripts available upon request